I think crypto would go up far faster
than people realize
>> Bitco
that that type of move to me and the
reason I say it with conviction the more
I'm talking to people let's say
traditional finance so related to the
banks cuz remember the banks are out
there telling people they're ready for
this they're going to be involved you
know all this stuff tokenization
pension funds need regulations what's
going on guys today we got a great
conversation with Jordi Visser in this
When we talk about what's going on with
oil, inflation, why the doomers are
wrong, why the stock market's going
higher, why Bitcoin's going higher, why
the AI companies are going higher,
what's going on with Astra, Grockbot,
how Jordy's using these technologies,
and then we even get into what's going
on with Kevin Walsh, Scott Bessant,
President Trump, are you going to bet
against the White House? Should you
think that the market is going higher?
And what does all this mean for your
portfolio? This one is fun. It's
informative, and I promise you're going
to learn something. Here's my latest
conversation with Jordy Visser. All
right, Jordy. I hear a lot of people in
the macro world talking about interest
rates and oil. I know people have been
talking to you about this recently. Uh
when I'm using AI, when I'm thinking
about Bitcoin, and then I hear someone
talking about interest rates and oil, my
brain is telling me, "Oh, yeah, that's
what we're supposed to think about in
the macro world, but my heart's kind of
telling me like, does that stuff really
matter anymore?" What do you think?
Well, it depends what you mean by does
it matter. For me, I love it. Um, in the
video I did this past weekend, I was as
direct as possible.
We're worried
about whether the Fed is going to raise
25 basis points. And I think the curve
says they're going to raise 25, but
maybe there'll be one more, possibly two
more before they come back down.
Why anyone would care about this when
earnings are growing 30 plus%. Is beyond
me. Why anyone would care about this
when, as I showed in the video, there is
no rate sensitivity
to the AI trade. Zero. Like despite what
people want to believe and the bare porn
that goes everywhere with like, oh,
rates are going higher. These guys can't
raise rates. Their CDS is blowing out.
Um,
progress is moving right now at a pace
so fast and is accelerating by the day.
Not by the week anymore, by the day. The
models are getting released. I was
talking about Grockbot the last two
weeks. Today we'll talk about Astra. I
don't I I mean I have Grockbot doing
things for me, but it's not even in
league of anything I can do with Astra
now, which is now combining the agentic
side with the chat, with the work, with
images, with everything else. Um, so
when people talk about rates and yeah, I
I had a bunch of conversations this week
where I'd get a text message from again
people I've known in the business a long
time starting with the market's going to
fall because rates are going higher and
oil is going higher. And I'm like, did
you watch my video? Like year-over-year
oil for the sixth contract
is up 20% from where it was a year ago.
Why do you care about this? Just because
you see a chart that shows it making the
highest price for the December contract
when it's below where it was. Didn't we
just go through this stupidity with
every oil person saying that we'd be I
mean we were supposed to be out of
gasoline in California during July.
So like if some if people are that wrong
and now we're 6 7 months from the
beginning of the war and we've now heard
that they're building pipelines so that
Hormuz is not as important or not
important at all at some point 3 years
from now. Why do you don't think the
market is smart enough to look through
this? But most importantly again I'll
say it. If earnings were only growing 5%
a year and if the economy was sensitive
to interest rates because what was
driving the economy was like what was
driving the economy before the great
financial crisis which was housing rate
sensitive stuff. I I I'd worry but the
economy is now digital. The economy is
not based on what we thought it was with
autos and this. We know that people are
not going out and borrowing money to buy
housing. We know they're not going out
borrowing money to buy cars the way they
did, but the household net worth is
going higher because profit margins are
booming and the stock market's going
higher. So, I just think when I listen
to a are we going to raise 25 or not and
oil's up and 10ear yields are up 35 to
40 basis points since July. I just think
people are they're missing the story for
what's happening and this is a
reflection that people just either don't
believe in AI or they don't use it. I
have a uh a new framework to put people
bucket-wise in. There's static people
and dynamic people. What I mean by that
is usually you think about I want people
who work for me or work with me or I
work for who are dynamic. They're
constantly learning. They're constantly
evolving. They're constantly improving.
Dynamic people is the same thing like a
volatile asset, right? You need
volatility for it to go up. So I think
people who are intelligent and want
returns, they're drawn to dynamic and
volatile. But actually you can put
people in bucket of do they think
statically or dynamically. So for
example uh tariffs are going to lead to
all these crazy prices blah blah
whatever. Static people just looked at
it as the tariff increases that means
that inflation increases. Dynamic people
say well if tariffs increase then does
domestic manufacturing increase does
this happen? Does this have what are the
other tools the government has to blunt
the effects? Oh maybe it's not going to
be as big of a problem. Oil is another
good example right now. If we go into
Iran, then oil will spike. And if oil
spikes, then that means that every
single person's paying $10 at the gas
pump, and you know, we're going to blow
out inflation, etc. Dynamic people
think, well, what if we have our own oil
or Venezuelan oil or maybe we have a
pipeline that we build or maybe the
economy isn't as stuck with the oil
sensitivity that it used to be. And so
when you think about this like static
verse dynamic, I actually think that
almost all of the like you know fear
porn kind of doomsday predicting is
people who are just looking at it from a
in this moment in time X happened so Y
has to happen cuz I've read it in a
textbook but actually the people who are
on the internet they are so used to the
speed of information the dynamic nature
and they've seen this play out enough
times now where almost all of the
doomsday saying is coming from like the
traditional world of people who are just
now like getting on the internet but the
people who have been on the for a long
time and I would put the AI people, the
crypto people, etc. They're actually not
bearish at all. Like they're super
bullish almost to the point where
actually they're getting accused of
being too optimistic, you know, that AGI
is going to like, you know, kill
humanity. Like I mean like crazy crazy
stuff. So I do think in a weird way it
maybe it's me just rationalizing being
terminally online now is such an
advantage because it keeps your brain
from like getting to be hard cement and
looking at the world statically, but
like what you're describing is really
just a dynamic view of how the economy
is playing out.
So yeah, the only thing I would disagree
with what you said at the very end there
is I think being online is super
critical all the time as opposed to be
sitting at a job and maybe looking at a
screen, but you also have to be curious
enough to look at all angles from a
story. If you just get caught watching
Fox News or or MSNBC, you're not really
changing your brain. Um, I think the
point you're making, so let me use an
analogy and just say, um, you know, one
of the great things about being a sports
fan and especially using the Knicks, if
you go back to Jaylen Brunson in college
and you look at him today and you would
have asked
a million people when he came out of
Villanova and was a second round draft
pick, if he would become one of the top
10 players in the world, the answer
would be zero chance. Like, he's not
going to morph into that. And they would
use the traditional things of, well,
he's not athletic enough. He's short.
Like, he's how how is that going to turn
into something? You still have people
that said, you can't win a championship
with your best player being someone like
Jaylen Rose, even when he had evolved
into an all-star.
>> The thing is Jaylen Brunson got better
every single year.
>> Um, that is the whole point of AI right
now. And if you're living on the past
when historically oil's gone higher and
like people will say inflation's high
and I'm like core CPI is 2.4%
year-over-year.
You pick the highest one PCE core
year-over-year which is going to be
revised. It changed and Kevin Worsh has
publicly said he doesn't agree with PCA
cores being he's got a whole group
getting together to figure out what they
should look at. I I just think people in
this dynamic side um and as someone who
grew up this way, I was trained to be a
trader. I sat in front of screens minute
by minute. If people haven't done it, I
mean, you get caught thinking every
single thing that comes out for a second
matters in some big scheme. So, when
people text me now and I don't have that
side, I'm like working on AI and this
happened to me uh when the PPI came out.
People were like, "Oh, stocks care about
this." And I remember saying like, "What
are you are you kidding me? What what do
you mean they care about this?
>> But is that an opportunity? Like is it
is it almost like hey let let the market
react to the old world you know economic
data points etc. And then you could
almost arbitrage and say I have a medium
to long-term view on these and so when
they dislocate based on these short-term
metrics just like have emotional control
and capitalize on it.
>> Yes. So he this gets into the market
structure thing and I believe we've
talked about this before and I think
everyone who works on Wall Street will
laugh at this.
Everyone who works at a hedge fund and
having done it and having people work
for me, they really are measured in many
many ways minuteto minute like they have
a draw down level which means that if
something happens in their portfolio and
it draws down 50 basis points on a day
when they're running a market neutral
portfolio and they they're only allowed
to have a 5% draw down. Well, they've
now lost onetenth of what they can lose.
Will it affect their emotion? Of course.
and they start extrapolating that this
could get worse. What is happening in
the market structures? I think you
should break it into three simple
buckets. One is there's the active
traders that have a a draw down level
where their capital will change and
their kids won't be able to go to
private school anymore. You have AI
agents which don't have any kids and
don't care about anything and their job
is just to make money. They don't have
the emotion that or the the the bars
that that they have fixed rules but they
don't have that stuff. And then you have
retail traders sitting at home or anyone
that has a longer time horizon that
doesn't have to respond to oh the PPI.
And that's to your point. Now that I'm
in that crowd, meaning I'm managing my
own money, I want bad news to happen at
a time when people are panicking,
especially when it comes to crypto where
I think we're at the beginning of a mega
bull market. It helps me to be able to
get entry points into things if these
guys are worried. I think the agents do
respond to what the hedge fund people
are reacting to. Meaning, oh,
historically, if the PBI comes out a
little bit hotter and rates go higher,
then we need to sell stocks. And the
agents go, fine, we're going to sell
stocks, too. We're going to jump in
front of you. But then the next day, the
agents don't care about what happened
the day before. They're looking at
what's going to happen today. What are
the hedge fun guys doing today? Okay,
I'm going to go buy in front of them.
And I think this is becoming a a very
dangerous game because when I talk to
people who are still managing money, the
market, they complain about it. It's not
easy to trade because you're getting
these herkyjerky moves every day and
there's no consistency. And so my belief
is that we are in a speed of a game that
has changed dramatically. And the people
that have the big advantage now are the
people that can look through it and say,
"Well, I know the earnings of the S&P
are going to be up 20% next year." So,
and I know there's not going to be a
recession. I know rates don't matter. I
know oil doesn't matter. So, if these
guys are going to over overreact to this
stuff, well, it gives me a better entry
point. I think that's what's happening
for a lot of different people in the
marketplace.
>> Are the Bitcoin and crypto people better
suited to invest today because they've
been through so much volatility in such
a short period of time?
>> Yeah, it goes further than that. Um,
the question I get asked most by people
getting into crypto now that I've spent
a lot of time there is how do we value
it? And I've started I'm going to write
a paper this week or I already I already
wrote 75% of it. Um I had to do a lot of
research. I had to find a person which I
did and I'm going to show it on the
video this week who went through a
metric and the reason this person was
interesting he he's part of the Ethereum
or was I think he's still part of the
Ethereum foundation. He was also part of
the Salana whatever it was foundation.
Um
the interesting part is he really talks
about
valuing and let's just take Ethereum
because that's where his focus is
as the ecosystem and its most similar
comparison is the internet. And so
regardless I don't like people getting
into philosophical debates. I'm old
enough to remember the way people valued
the internet back in the '9s. And people
have to think about this now. Most
people that we're talking to were not
trading during the '9s. During the '90s
when the internet started and when we
led into the dotcom bubble, the way they
were valuing Amazon was eyeballs. And he
mentions like we didn't have metrics
back then. And he goes through like it
was eyeballs, it was clicks, it was a
bunch of different things, but it didn't
mean anything. Now he was involved with
Napster, so he's an original
peer-to-peer person. That's what makes
his angle so interesting. I also think
he's very academic and boring, which is
why whenever I've asked people in
crypto, they don't either they've never
heard of him or they've never followed
him. I listened to him. I went, "This
guy finally hit on it." Like for crypto
to be valued as something, we don't know
what the metrics are going to be. And
we're starting to see that with Robin
Hood chain. I
>> what's going on there?
>> We're the volumes are picking up.
Everything is starting to go with
tokenization. And again, if I go through
the this year, the importance of the
ecosystem and I think of pers, I think
of prediction markets, I think of all of
the things like SpaceX, what its
valuation was before it went public and
how quickly the market kind of migrated
around to it. This 24/7 active trading
and what Robin Hood chain built on
Ethereum is doing through Arbitum is
literally saying we're at the beginning
of tokenization. Like we're we're
literally at the beginning of it. Now,
we've talked about it a lot and I've
said that the network effects will kick
in if you take what's happening now and
the person's name that I was referencing
and I I I don't know the proper way to
pronounce it, but William Goyabber.
Okay, if you go back, he was on a he did
a TED talk somewhere around 2015.
I asked Chat GPT from the transcript to
go through and say how much of what he
said back then about the blockchain, it
was all on the blockchain is correct.
and it went through and said his vision
of what was happening was about an eight
and a half out of 10. If we drill down
to each separate component, it's about a
five, five out of 10. But 8 and a half
out of 10 for the general thing of the
importance of the blockchain and what
will happen eventually over time. And so
the Robin Hood chain, fast forward 11
years,
that's what's going on right now. like
we're starting to get to the point where
tokenization is happening and even
though it's being driven predominantly
by memecoins at this point in terms of
the volumes that's what should be
happening and I mentioned bucket last
week and I said this is a memecoin but
with other component parts of the
programmable side that people should be
paying attention to because it's a
leadin to what is going to happen more
and more on Robin Hood chain. So for me
in thinking about the crypto side and
what's actually gone on, I again believe
that people that were trained in crypto,
number one, they deal with speed. Number
two, they deal with quote unquote pump
and dump or things that move a certain
way. They get used to the volatility.
They've been bred on it. But the other
thing is how do you value a market, the
S&P 500, in a world that of exponential
as opposed to linear? And that's why
when you go to my website and you go
look, I've got a V for Visser. The left
side of the V is linear. The right side
is a parabola. And the reason it's a
parabola is because when things start
changing quickly, the only people, in my
opinion, that can deal with the
movements are people that have been
trained in trading in chaos. I grew up
in emerging markets. I think crypto is a
very similar thing. This episode is
brought to you by Lava. The Lava card is
the first credit card that allows you to
earn up to 5% back in Bitcoin on every
single purchase. Most cards have steep
annual fees and unclear points programs,
but the Lava card offers a much better
deal. Earn real Bitcoin every time that
you spend. Plus, there's no annual fee.
There's zero FX fees, and zero spread
when you spend internationally. On top
of that, Lava gives you access to a
Bitcoin line of credit, yield on cash,
instant stable coin deposits and
withdrawals, on and off ramps to and
from your bank account, and much, much
more. With Lava, you can borrow against
your Bitcoin at the lowest rates, earn
yield, move money globally, and stack
Bitcoin with each and every purchase you
make. Most financial services squeeze
you with high fees, confusing rewards
programs. Lava keeps it simple, and they
help you build your long-term savings
via your everyday spend. Visit
lava.xyz/p
to get started in just a few minutes
today. lava.xyz/p
to get started today. Robin Hood chain
is like explain maybe just in a little
bit of detail what exactly is happening
there and uh it seems like they really
have pushed themselves to the frontier
in terms of they now I think make more
revenue off of the prediction markets
than they do off of stocks. They have
really doubled down on agentic trading.
Um I think public many others have done
that as well. Um, but it does feel like
Robin Hood, which started out as like
come buy stocks and don't pay a
commission, was pretty dead square in
the center of like traditional finance.
And the like challenger type attitude
was around fees.
>> Mhm.
they have completely migrated to like
let's be on the frontier of the products
we offer and how people interact and and
has become almost more of a challenger
you know type uh neo bank um or like
fintech than where they started which is
very unique. Usually you start off as
like the most extreme version and then
you become more of like the man, right?
They seem to be going the opposite
direction with at their size and scale
seems, you know, a little bit uh
unexpected.
>> Well, let's go back to the title of my
research. AI crypto macro nexus. So,
what's the macro part of Robin Hood?
Well, it's the original stock trading
side. What's the crypto side? Well, now
we've got Robin Hood chain. What's the
AI side? Well, we have the Agentic
plugin that's going to this. Um, I think
what Vlad has done and he spoke this
week at at a Goldman Sachs conference.
You mentioned some of the numbers. They
are, and I wrote a paper on this for
people who are in the traditional
finance world. Robin Hood is the company
to go look at to figure out what this
means in terms of this merge that's
happening. It's the problem that people
have is how do we value this? Well,
tokenization is something that you and I
have talked about and it is probably the
I'm at Freedom Tech next week. Are you
going to Freedom Tech? Okay. Um, I'm
looking forward to doing my presentation
down there. And the reason is because
when I put the slides together, one of
them is about this bridge being built
right now. And tokenization for me is
the bridge between the two worlds
because Robin Hood has a community of
traders. And I mentioned last week that
when I went to a Robin Hood event last
year to speak on a panel, I was blown
away by the community aspect. Now, this
is after I had been at your event. I'd
been at Raul Powell's event and I saw
this community which was very different
than events I went to on Wall Street.
There's no community. It's literally
like you put a bunch of people to get
together, they want to kill each other.
It's it's a competitive world. While a
community of Robin Hood, of crypto is
very different. And so, I think Robin
Hood merges not just these technologies
together, I think it merges this
community aspect. And it's very easy to
take the community that is trying to
make money as a group trading on stocks.
They don't care whether it's Palunteer.
They don't care whether it's Micron.
They don't care whether it's
Ethereum, whether it's a meme, whether
it's Bucket. It doesn't really matter to
them. They're just trying to make money.
And they're doing it in a way. And Robin
Hood has, yes, they've changed their
business enough that the reason I wrote
a paper on them was they got a couple
upgrades last week. and specifically
Morgan Stanley publicly upgraded the
stock. It was not based on the crypto
revenues though. It was based on other
things and the fact that the company was
becoming a little bit like Apple,
meaning multiple service revenue
streams. And I think that's the thing to
go through when you go back to the
William Goyabber stuff. I believe that
we are leaving a world of revenues and
we are entering a world of two things
that have value. trust and that's where
Ethereum becomes really important. It's
where Bitcoin becomes really important
because I think in a world of AI people
are underestimating the amount of
hackings and the lack of trust that will
be there and the trust that a company
will be here in a decade and we can talk
more about that with some of the things
with Astra. But I think terminal value
is declining. So trust is number one.
The second thing is velocity of of of
it's the flow. It's the volume. It is
just the mass of speed. And AI agents
get a hell of a lot more done than
humans. So, we're leaving a world where
human beings were doing the trading and
doing the consuming and doing
everything. And we're getting to one
where AI agents are doing more and more.
And so, Robin Hood is built for that.
You mentioned the agentic trading side.
I just did a video which is going to go
up on my subscriber wall this week to
teach people how to build and back test
a model using a a a GitHub code that I
put together that they can then pull in,
stick it in their own LLM and then back
test something to create a signal model
and I go through a training episode of
how they can do this and where the edges
are for the humans and where the edges
are for AI so that they and I think
retail traders are very good at this so
I think it's going to work well but then
take that information and plug it into
Robin Hood. And it's not just Robin
Hood. Mumu has this. Interactive Brokers
have this. Like the Agentic side where
you can do it and you can paper trade
it. You don't have to put money in. But
I think it's really important for
parents to have their kids do this
because doing this type of stuff is the
beginning of training your children on
how to be entrepreneurs. And I've talked
about my son on this point. I don't talk
about my daughters as much because
they're in the healthc care field.
They're helping people. My son's going
to be more of an entrepreneur, but he's
using agents daily. And I think for
parents out there and everyone, what
Robin Hood is allowing you to do is
actually become a training ground for
building stuff. So, I think of Robin
Hood definitely in kind of the Apple App
Store place, multiple revenue streams,
and it's expanding not just with
prediction markets, but also with what
they've been doing right now with the
trading side on Robin Hood chain.
>> You mentioned earlier that you think
crypto is on the cusp of a very big bull
market. Is that a in the month of
September type thing? Is that a through
the end of Q4 we should expect this?
What how do you think about timing for
the next great Bitcoin bull market?
>> Well, I and I hate I hate for people to
have to sit there and acknowledge it
this way. So, quarter to date when we
come to sit in here the best performing
asset by far of all the major assets and
I I'll say major assets by anything
that's worth that has a valuation of
let's say more than a hundred billion.
Ethereum is by far the best performing
asset. Like not even close. Uh it's I
think it's almost double Bitcoin quarter
to date. While the S&P 500's around
flat, NASDAQ's around flat. So we've so
far had Bitcoin and crypto outperforming
for a quarter while stocks have done
nothing. Um I think that's good. That's
very good. But the importance of that is
the low correlation. But it also means
the next thrust to me stocks will go up
with crypto with it. So, I do think
we're at the beginning stages of getting
away. I have been very surprised at how
I don't want to say negative, but how
little people want to embrace this. I
don't hear crypto people as like uber
bullish. At least, let's say the regular
people that I talk to on a they're
they're skeptical because
>> the crypto people are skeptical about
Bitcoin and crypto's recent rally.
>> Well, that we're not going to retest the
lows first. Um
>> they're they're worried that we will.
>> Yeah, they're worried that we will. And
I guess that makes sense. That's the way
it should be after a bare market.
>> They got four cycles psychosis, you
know. Yeah. It's like, hey, October's
the bottom. That's what they've that's
what they've been told. They line up
their charts. I get it. I you know, I'm
starting to lean more towards how
important the Clarity Act um situation
is. Not it's not going to stop what's
going on regardless of what happens cuz
they're going to put rules in place. But
if anything positive happens on on
clarity and it's funny you you go into X
you read Brian Armstrong you read you
know um I forget Patrick's name what's
the
>> Patrick Whit I mean they've been very
positive this week that it's going to
surprise the prediction markets which
are below 20% it but I think that's for
this year we if we got anything positive
on clarity
I think crypto would go up far faster
than people realize
>> big 100k if we get clarity Yes, I that
that type of move to me and the reason I
say it with conviction,
the more I'm talking to people, let's
say traditional finance, so related to
the banks, cuz remember the banks are
out there telling people they're ready
for this, they're going to be involved,
you know, all this stuff, tokenization,
pension funds need regulations for this.
And so for the ecosystem as a whole,
which is really the most important thing
to me, um, Bitcoin can keep going higher
and it can
drag a little bit of glass on here.
Um, uh, Bitcoin can rally high.
>> You ever seen someone get wounded on a
podcast? You just did.
>> It's all good. Uh,
um, if clarity goes through, I think the
ecosystem will be valued higher
immediately because I think this opens
up investment from pension funds, which
are critical to the overall size of the
money coming in. I think they need
regulation. I think they need something
to be able to again they're fiduciary.
They can't just jump into something.
Bitcoin has been around long enough that
they can do that. But I think investing
in the ecosystem, which is what the
entrepreneurs need. I don't think it's a
venture thing. I I think it's a pension
thing. And I I think if clarity goes
through, it's a big deal. It does feel
to me like um clarity can't hurt and not
like by it not being passed it can't
hurt but it would be a a net new buyer
entering the market or at least getting
more excited and kind of sending us
upward. Um on AI there's been a ton of
stuff that's come out. Uh GPT live one I
think it's called like the voice um
Astra got released. Uh we got a whole
debate as to whether OpenAI was
unethically looking at mathematicians uh
potential solutions to these uh century
old problems. Um we have a guy who uh
got a job at Anthropic for 6 weeks,
quit, says it AI is going to kill
everybody, but then somehow he's part of
like the Doomer crowd and they're all
retweeting him and like piling on. Seems
kind of like a scop, but unclear
what the hell is going on in AI.
I mean, there was like a year's worth of
progress in the last seven days.
>> Well, and you not only have that, I
mean, Paul Tudtor Jones wrote an op-ed
in the Wall Street Journal and I think
uh I think Greg Jensen from Bridgewater
also came out um again on the risks with
AI and how um I think the I think
Jensen's thing was it's going to kill
people. Jensen said that.
>> Yeah, I've seen the news today or
something. Um here here's the thing. Um,
I am a person that believes that any
progress in AI from this point, we
should be expecting there to be
problems. I mean, I don't know if you
heard the Boston Scientific News this
week, but they had a hacking and they
basically said they're not going to meet
their earnings numbers for the rest of
this year and they had to take them down
and had an impact on some other stocks
like Striker. Uh, and then there was a
power plant hack in the UK. Uh, and I
think we got some information on Iran's
plans on hacking and everything.
>> This is a crazy story. Yeah. So, first
of all, I'm an investor in a company
called Galvanic. I'm going to give them
a shout out. Uh, somebody who worked uh
at the White House left and his whole
thing was we need to secure the critical
infrastructure in America from cyber
attacks. And when he first started
talking about this a couple years ago,
people are like, "What are you talking
about?" He's like, "Yeah, water
treatment plants, you know, power
plants, whatever."
Josh Steman looks like a genius right
now.
Like do not go short Joshua Stein. Uh so
that that's on the power plan stuff.
This Iran story is almost literally you
couldn't put it in a movie. So for those
who don't know, Iran was supposedly
taking their war plans, the Ayatollah's
funeral plans, uh targeting lists of
people, spreadsheets, all this stuff,
and they were feeding it to Claude. Now,
it does make sense like if you want
superhuman intelligence, it's probably
smarter than anyone in Iran cuz it's
smarter than anyone in the United
States. So, like, okay. Um, but then
Claude was like, "Wait a minute. We're
not going to let Iran use our computing
intelligence to
then plan killing people or all this
kind of crazy stuff." So, they had the
plans and I'm assuming they turned it
over to the government. Like
>> that's kind of the same thing that
OpenAI is being accused of on the
mathematician problem of like oh that's
uh you guys going to solve that century
old problem. It'd be a shame if we
figured out the exact same way to solve
the problem which I'm not saying that
they did it but if they are training the
model on the questions that are being
asked and then all of a sudden they
solved the problem.
>> It does feel like privacy does feel like
data security does feel like owning your
own intelligence is going to become
pretty important here.
All right. So,
we've we're for anyone who either
doesn't know these stories or doesn't
know the importance of both of them and
especially the the Navier Stokes part.
Um, if you're living in a world talking
about oil and interest rates going
higher, again, I I ju I just want to say
we are so far past everything now. Uh, I
asked Chachi PT what the IQ of Astra is
because I used Astra on um on lab on
Labor Day and I built a model a signal
model and it led me to doing the video
that I mentioned and the reason was that
I was blown away with the step function
change in this. Now I had talked about
Crockbot for two weeks here. Astra took
me to another level. So these stories
that are coming out, whether it's the
doomer story or whether it's the
progress story, uh the reality is AI is
here and it has a huge impact. When you
go through the astride and I listened to
an interview with Greg Brockman on TBPN,
um where when you listen to it,
basically we've reached the point where
okay, we used to have chat and we had
openclaw. Then we had chat, co-work, and
openclaw.
Well, now we have
co-work and claude code and claude chat.
What Brockman said is basically
everything now is inside
chat GPT.
what happened with what they did and I
think people should spend time on the
Navier Stokes thing from and if you
listen to Moonshots from this week they
go through everything but 100,000 GPUs I
believe that's what that number is now
100,000 GPUs so this was brute force and
this gets back into like anyone who
thinks open source is going to compete
with the brute force to get you know a
century old uh formula
math problem
figured out
leading to physics problems that will be
solved. And when physics problems, if
people really want to spend time on it,
which I did this morning for a while, we
talked about it before we sat down. I
mean, we're talking about terminal value
for the S&P 500 changing for any
physical company, any mining companies,
anything. Now it won't change it for the
earnings for the next 3 years, 4 years,
but 5 years and out, as I keep saying
all the time, I think you have a
question of whether these companies that
are doing old traditional things of
mining are really going to be able to
make money ever again if we've got
solutions that get down to physics and
get into things for the heart and things
for drug discovery and thing everything
that you can imagine. And that's why you
have to spend time not kind of reading
about Navier Stokes but just going to
chat GPT and say what does this mean for
the world and I'll have a slide on that
in there from my own exploration for 30
minutes to learn about it. So AI is
moving so fast and the compounding of
these models is going at a speed which
is unbelievable that when Jensen Yuang
goes on stage and says congratulations
to Open AI on hitting AGI.
Imagine in a week where a Jensen Yuang,
>> godfather of AI,
>> says, "Congratulations for reaching AGI
and the front page of the stock market
has Besset saying, "I am the house on
one side and on the other side you have
everyone panicking over rates and oil."
The week that Jenzen Wong says that in
AGI, everyone's worried about that. And
that is the reason why I just think for
people that are using what's happening
on the news and what's happening in the
market, the S&P 500 is unchanged or at
least as of yesterday, it was unchanged
since like June 2nd.
But we've made all this progress in AI.
We've solved all these things. We've
jumped. The market's completely
mispriced relative to the progress
that's happening. And that means that
it's like keeping a water on or ball
underwater and at some point it explodes
higher. And that's why I said I think
crypto as just a segue into why it'll go
higher. Well, it did really well when
stocks couldn't move and all these panic
fears when what would happen if oil went
down for a week and rates went down for
5 days and we got the rate hike and
everyone's like, "Okay, now what?" It's
like the midterms, Jordy. The midterms
are going to kill this and the Dems are
going to win this and data centers are
going to be I'm like, "So, I guess the
day the midterms are over and you turn
around and you've been worried about
this, what are you going to say when the
stock market goes higher?" Like,
sometimes the Trump paid for it. That's
what they're going to say. They're 100%
going to say, "He he said he's going to
give out stimulus 100%."
Sometimes having done this a long time,
the best thing for the market
>> is just getting through the events and
having what was expected at this point.
>> The Dems are expected to win
>> everything regardless of what people
say. At this point, the market expects
the Fed to raise 25.
>> Mhm.
>> Okay. That's what's expected.
>> Do you think it's going to happen? Do I
think they'll raise 25?
>> Yeah.
>> I I don't think it's a 70% chance. And
>> 81% on poly market as of this morning.
25 basis point. take
I so I'm going to I'm going to say I
don't think it's going to happen. I'm
also gonna say I kind of hope it does
happen so we can just get rid of it
because
>> I think the more likely scenario or the
one that's the most bullish for the
market because if he doesn't go it just
leaves up that he could go
forward. Um if he goes and basically
says
okay we I did this because the committee
is split
and because I felt like the arguments
were towards this side as an insurance
and I believe it's better to do 25 now
and get ahead of things if they keep
going to open up the possibility but I
don't think we're going to do any more.
So basically a dovish hike that would
satisfy the Fed credibility. It might
help the long end of the market. It
would give people something. I don't
think it matters. Like I said, I don't
know why 25 basis points up or down
matters to anyone as long as earnings
are growing. And unlike 2022, and every
time I see someone in the market do
this, 2022 was a very unique situation.
We were coming from incredibly low
rates. AI was not a part of the
equation. So we didn't have this massive
capex and earnings boom based on that.
We were coming out of a recession
obviously and we had inflation up at 10%
or nine and change. Now we've got core
inflation at 2.4% in terms of core CPI.
We already have rates at this level and
we were going the debate wasn't 25. It
was do we go 50, do we go 75? And so we
raised rates really quickly in 2022. And
then once we slowed down and basically
came to the end, that's when you wanted
to buy stock. So I just think uh the
best thing for the market would probably
be raising 25 with some kind of dovish
message that this was an insurance
thing. And since inflation is already on
the low side there, but it would not
surprise me if behind the scenes the
pressure from the White House and what
Donald Trump wants. Uh, I think we all
make mistakes when we start fading what
Besson and Trump are going to do to make
sure what they want to have happen
happens. Today's episode is brought to
you by Token 2049. The largest
conference in crypto is back. Token 2049
will host 25,000 people, 300 speakers,
and a,000 plus side events in Singapore
on October 7th and 8th at Marina Bay
Sands. The speaker list is absolutely
stacked. Shane Copeland from Poly
Market, Jeff Yan from Hyperlquid, Adena
Freriedman from NASDAQ, Arthur Hayes,
Bellagi, and Eric Trump. Crypto and
traditional finance in the same
building, which tells you a lot about
where this is going. And the conference
runs right into F1 weekend, so the whole
thing turns into one giant week. If
you're headed to Singapore, use code
POMP 10 for 10% off your ticket. Token
2049, October 7th and 8th in Singapore.
Go check them out in the link in the
description. Today's episode is brought
to you by Simple Mining. Bitcoin mining
has a reputation for being complicated,
risky, and hard to evaluate as a real
investment. If you're considering mining
in 2026, what actually matters isn't
headline profitability. It's uptime,
repairs, and whether the operation is
run like a real business. That's why
I've been using Simple Mining. They're
based in Cedar Falls, Iowa, and they run
a white glove hosting operation where
you own your miners. You choose your own
pool, and you have Bitcoin sent directly
to your wallet. They were featured on
the Inc. 5,000 lists as the fastest
growing company in Iowa with over 40,000
machines under management. What stands
out to me is execution. They have the
number one rated ASIC repair center. And
for the first 12 months, repairs are
included. If mining margins get tight,
you can pause with no penalties. And if
you want to resize or upgrade your
fleet, there's a marketplace to resell
equipment instead of being stuck. To
help people think it through whether
mining actually makes sense right now,
they put together a short resource
called the 2026 Bitcoin mining
blueprint. It walks through the five
mistakes investors make when allocating
to mining and they also explain how to
avoid them before deploying capital. If
it sounds interesting to you, you can
get it for free at simplemining.io/p.
That's simplemining.io/p.
Go check it out today and see if you
should get into the mining game.
If they raise rates, I will understand
why. If I'm a betting man, there is a
negative% chance they're cutting or
they're raising rates. And it all falls
down to we are going to learn a lesson
that we have learned in the past, which
is the Fed is not independent.
And the same reason that Jerome Powell
cut rates right before the election is
going to be the same reason why I don't
think Kevin War's going to raise rates
right now. And if you have a job, you
got a boss. And if you got a boss,
you may say you're independent, but you
kind of listen. You may even argue back,
but the message kind of gets through.
And so, let's see, right? But if they
raise rates, I will understand. I I
think that the data is, you know, kind
of iffy and there probably is going to
be some disagreement on and there has
been disagreement at the FOMC, but I do
think that the politics of it all is uh
heavily mispriced or misallocated in
terms of its importance.
>> So, let's go let's go back this way
because I I again, let's say there's
three possibilities. There's the the
Trump pressure one. Doesn't raise.
>> Okay.
>> There's the
Okay, fine. I'm going to raise, but I'm
also going to be dovish.
>> Mhm.
>> And then there's the third one, which is
I'm going to raise and be hawkish. Oh,
>> there's a fourth. What if he cuts?
>> Okay, let's leave that one alone. We'll
put that at zero.
>> Bitcoin to a million.
Um, I I think if I was going to say then
if though if we I think you can take one
and two and and put them together
because I think a hike with a dovish
message is the same as in fact I
actually think it might be better for
the market than not hiking because to
your point I think the Fed credibility
thing will become an issue and the
question is what does that mean? Now, if
the dollar falls off and everyone goes
through this, fine. But if rates shoot
higher because he doesn't cut because he
doesn't raise, I I think that might be a
bigger issue. But let's assume that the
first two are the I mean, I'm guessing
that those are 90% when combined. I
don't think I don't think raising rates
with a hawkish message.
>> Yeah, I don't think that's
>> I I don't think it is either based on
the data that we've had over since the
last meeting.
>> I don't think it is strategic for them.
I don't think the data supports it, nor
do I think that's what they want to do.
Correct. Right. So, it's like you're
kind of three strikes you're out on
that. Um, it's an interesting way to
think about maybe raising and being
dovish is the same as just leaving. Um,
but you may get an advantage from it.
Um,
>> let's see. But, you know, I don't know
if you got the message. Uh, we are the
house now.
>> I mean, did you hear his uh his
commentary uh this morning?
>> No.
>> Or maybe it was late last night, but it
was all over uh X today. He went on uh
Steve Bannon's war room of all places
>> and he said, "If the uh Bloomberg
terminal bros are upset with me, then so
be it."
>> And he's just like, "Look, I'm going to
do what I'm going to do. I kind of don't
care." But uh whether it is the uh uh
commentary around the Edmonton
submarines when he was talking about
Canada, the Bloomberg terminal bros, I
mean, this guy is a all-time
communicator. And I think that he's been
uh rubbing shoulders with Trump for a
while now cuz he is definitely finding
his uh you know his voice if you will.
>> I I I mean
I I lived in the world of Wall Street.
I've known Scott Pesson a long time or
at least known of him a long time and I
have had many many people talk to me
about him. The same thing with Kevin
Walsh.
>> Um work with many people who worked for
them, been around them. This is not the
Scott Bessant that
>> he was not an elite talker forever.
>> I mean, I I remember before he got the
before he got the job when we were
talking about if he got the job, a lot
of people were saying I don't know if
he'd be able to handle which Trump's
going to go. I think actually he's
incredible.
>> He's become in many ways. So that's why
I I do agree with you that and it's the
reason why I think when people are
challenging like rates, it's not that
I 10ear rates to me
should be 200 basis points higher. Okay.
Now, that is not what the administration
wants and it's not what the Fed wants
either. And I say that based on well,
what's the the point that we'd actually
be restrictive on the economy? And I
think tenure rates need to be
significantly higher to be restrictive.
In the past,
tenure rates were about 200 basis points
above nominal GDP. Well, nominal GDP is
6%. So, theoretically, you should be
eight. Now, that all changed in 1997.
And in 1997, we went below during the
Asian financial crisis, and we never got
back above except for periods of time
when nominal GDP collapsed during
recessions. When nominal GDP was stable,
tenure rates were always below it. The
reason I say it should be above it,
well, we no longer are depend. This
economy is not dependent on autos and
housing. Like I can't say loud enough to
people, this is not an interest rate
sensitive market.
>> If rates at higher level, everyone that
has cash is getting more money in their
bank account. And so we're just at a
point of time where transfer payments
are huge, meaning the government is
handing out money to people that don't
have enough money. And then at the on
the other side, the AI trade has nothing
to do with tenure rates at this point.
And I can't say this loud enough to
everyone who listens to doomers and all
this stuff. Well, they need to go borrow
money.
That's ridiculous. I mean, it really is
ridiculous. I am uh the unofficial
president of uh the Scott Besson fan
club. And um you know, uh Mr. Treasury
Secretary, if you're watching this, uh
talk your I I love it. I I think
it's amazing. I think that uh he does
calm the market compared to, you know,
Trump's kind of erratic uh craziness
sometimes. And uh I actually think that
they are a pretty good duo because it's
kind of like carrot and stick to a
degree. Yep.
>> Although Besson maybe is, you know, he's
developing a stick um in that he is the
house now. Um but if you go and you look
at the other side of this maybe kind of
private sector, you know, um man, they
really need the entrepreneurs and the AI
companies and you know, uh the data
centers, etc. perform and in a very
weird way there's an unofficial public
private partnership that is attacking
the problems of the US economy
>> and the private sector is doing a damn
good job of getting this technology out
creating you know uh jobs and growth and
productivity and revenue and earnings
growth and like all the things that
actually are providing a lot of uh
relief for the Treasury Secretary the
Fed you know they would be in a much
more dire situation if they did not have
the productivity gain and the technology
innovation that's happening. And so I
think that the macro people really focus
on like reading the tea leaves and you
know kind of playing the you know um
astrology for men game of like what are
they going to say? What are they going
to do?
>> Mhm.
>> But damn that private sector is rocking
and when you look at it holistically I
don't know. It's pretty hard to be
bearish.
>> Well here's here's the thing you said
that I think people should um keep in
mind. So, let's just say you've got
Trump and you've got Besson and we're
saying that they're aligned in their
thinking at this point. Okay, great.
Besson also said this week the US cannot
lose the AI race to China. So, when
you're betting against AI or you're
saying I think it's a bubble and go and
like okay, you're betting against Besson
and Trump who are literally saying we're
going to win the race with China because
it's too important. At the same time,
every AI person is in direct
conversation with the White House.
>> They have rooms at the White House. They
literally live at the White House.
>> Exactly.
>> These dudes are there every week.
>> Yeah. And and you can call it what do
you want inside? I really don't care.
But why would you bet against this? Like
why would you be fighting against it?
Now, there's one other person that
matters. Kevin Worsh. They not only
chose Kevin Worsh, they in his
testimonies. First of all, he's pro
crypto, pro Bitcoin, he also believes in
what Greenspan did and believes that AI
is a changing technology to where the
Fed has to change.
>> Mhm.
>> So, when you put it all together, the
people who are bearish, number one, they
seem to be betting against AI. And I'm
telling you, they don't use it. If you
want to be bearish because you think
it's going to end the human race, I get
it. Like that is I don't get that. Okay,
but that's fine. If you want to do that,
the reason I say I get it, they're
basing it on the fact that AI is getting
too strong.
>> Mhm.
>> If you want to
>> They're like but they're almost bullish
on AI and they're like they're the most
bullish people.
>> Yeah.
>> It's cuz they're the ones who think that
it's going to be so good that it gets
out of control. If you want to bet
against it because of the arguments of
Michael Bur and Jim Chenos from a year
ago, a year ago, where they said this is
a bubble because they're saying these
chips will have a lifespan of it's not
there's no way. Well, the H100s,
go look at the price that's happened
year-over-year. They're higher than they
were back then. So that is like saying
that people get younger every year
because there's a depreciation on this
stuff. So when Gavin Baker, and I'll be
covering this, like when Gavin Baker
goes in there and says, "Do you realize
that everyone that owns these chips
running
basic a data center, the compute prices
today that they can sell at those things
is higher than they were a year ago. And
these chips are costing more. So if
people want So they basically bought
food a year ago before an inflationary
spike and they're able to market these
at higher prices cuz all the other
restaurants right now are charging
higher. So if people don't understand
what that means and Gavin Baker talked
about it, he believes that the cloud
providers, so the guys that are spending
all the money and taking all the debt
out, he said on Patrick Oshan's podcast
a month ago, and that was a month ago,
H100s are higher than even when they
were back then, that you'll be shocked
at how quickly the cloud providers will
start to have profits coming through,
not just from new data centers coming
out, but from the fact that the compute
prices that they can charge are higher
and their costs are actually lower on
the existing stuff they have. There's so
much in this that again you've got the
administration saying we're not going to
let this not happen. You have Worsh
Bessant Trump aligned on the same thing
believing in AI and believing in crypto
and you have market participants that
manage lots of money all the world's
money worried about things in a linear
fashion. The reason the market isn't
higher is because of the worries people
have. No question about it. And I want
to end with one more thing on this that
I I started talking to people about this
week. The beauty of Bitcoin at this
point is this magical number for me of
$2 trillion.
So Bitcoin's around a $2 trillion asset.
You know what else is around a $2
trillion asset?
>> Your bank account.
>> SpaceX.
Anthropic.
And I think after Astra, I think open
people are probably missing the boat on
OpenAI at this point. Let's assume
they're all worth two trillion. Isn't
that an interesting part of where the
market is? You have four things.
None of them make money. And I throw
Bitcoin into it. Doesn't make money.
These other three, let's assume they're
two trillion. They don't make money at
this point. They're spending the two
companies that have, you know, their ARR
looks great. They're spending a lot more
money than their monthly number. and
SpaceX. It's it's a thing based on time.
That is $8 trillion worth of things that
in my opinion are so important to the
future. And people are still talking
about the level of the Fed funds rate
and oil. You are not adapting to where
the world is today. You are still left
in a world of 20 years ago. I won't even
say 10 because you have to go back
before the iPhone. You have to go back
before the iPhone because all of this
stuff should have been washed from
people. It's the reason why I tell the
story all the time. I went to Silicon
Valley in 2013 to answer the question,
how can Amazon up be up 17,000%
since 1997? Yes, I want to say that to
everyone. The stock at that time when I
went there was up 17,000%.
And it still was really not making
money. Now, it was in 2013, but it
wasn't really in 20 in 2008. And I went
out there cuz I'm like, how can this
thing always make new highs after it
falls down? It's a bubble. It can't
possibly be real on the metrics that I
know. How can this be real? And I went
there and Singularity University changed
my life. And I never thought of the
world that way. You have to go back.
These people are telling you the world
is going to end. That's the reason they
go back to the.com bubble because it's
the only period before technology
actually was working when they can find
a time in history where okay, this is a
bubble. I will hope that those people
have a great day. I hope that they uh
enjoy themselves. I feel bad for their
children's portfolios uh cuz it's
probably not going to work out for them.
Make sure you subscribe to Jord's
YouTube page. Go to Jordiv Visser on
YouTube. And uh if you have not yet
signed up for Sylvia, go to
cfosilia.com. We'd love to have you. You
can uh use the latest greatest AI
technology. It won't kill you. It'll
help your portfolio. Go check it out at
cfosilia.com.